# **Edwin Huitz**

## Full-Stack Web Developer | Software Engineer

Washington, DC | 240-722-8771

edwinhuitz@gmail.com | www.github.com/EdwinHuitz | www.EdwinHuitz.xyz

### **Summary**

I specialize in front and backend web development, with the skill set to create anything from a basic personalized webpage to a complex social media website. Alongside this I also carry a growing expertise with Python, which can be used for data mining, machine learning, and universal application development.

#### Skills

HTML, HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, jQuery, Google OAuth, Passport.js, Python, Matplotlib, NumPy, Django, PostgreSQL, PHP, and Git

### **Recent Projects**

Honest Apartment Testimonies - CRUD website with authentication written in Python, Django, PSQL

**Numisma-List -** CRUD website with authentication written in Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Google OAuth, and Passport.js

Python Applets - A large set of single use Python applications written entirely in Python and 3rd-Party Python Libraries

## **Experience**

Personal Experience (2009 - 2020) - JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Bonanza - Numismatist (2015 - 2020)

General Assembly – Software Engineer Fellowship (2020 - 2020)

### Back-End (Python, Django, PostgreSQL, AWS, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB)

- · Enforced user restrictions which only allowed for logged in users to view certain pages
- Allowed users to Create, Read, Update, and Delete content with fluid consistency
- · Uploaded and hosted user's photos using Amazon Web Services
- · API routing, fetching, and 3rd Party user authentication using Google OAuth

### Front-End (React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)

- Responsive User Interface web design via JavaScript, React.js, and HTML5
- Post production React component creation and integration
- Styling using third party libraries such as Bootstrap and Materialize
- Extensive experience private API's such as profile data, user records, calendar/appointment information
- Extensive experience using 3<sup>rd</sup> Party API's such as Youtube, Google Maps, Spotify, Twitter, and others

### Python (Python, Matplotlib, NumPy)

Web scraping data and compiling relevant graphs of said data for COVID-19 infection/casualty rates

### **Education**

Full-Stack Software Engineering, General Assembly - 07 / 2020 - 10 / 2020

Computer Engineering, Montgomery College - 08 / 2012 – 08 / 2013